[up-tempo jazz playing]
[indistinct conversations]
Let's do it.
[clinking]
- Thank you, Sadie.
- Mm-hmm.
My friends, I am so proud
and happy to welcome you
to this celebration
of my son Xander
the new C.E.O.
of Harrington Media.
[male #1]
'Here, here.'
Where is
the little cuss, anyway?
Late for work already,
not a good sign.
Elizabeth, text him,
would you?
You got it.
Um, I am sure my husband
'has a very good excuse
for his..'
'Ah, there you are, Xander.'
[male #2]
'Bravo Xander.'
[crowd applauding]
[crowd gasping]
[murmuring]
[Cho]
That's what killed
Xander Harrington,
'and this is where he was
attacked.'
'Now, the blood trail
starts here'
'right where the letter opener
was found.'
The deputy coroner says it was
a single stab wound to the neck.
Now the blow sends him
backwards.
He slams his head,
goes down.
He's dazed, slowly bleeding out
for a good 20 minutes or so,
then somehow gathers himself up
and goes for help.
Coroner couldn't believe he even
made it out to the party.
Party which was for him.
Guy just got a big promotion.
Had a wife and kid.
How sad is that?
Sad. Anything else?
Well, according to the victim's
father, there was
a confidential business file on
this desk that's gone missing.
- Nothing else taken.
- What was the file about?
Plans for the "Daily Observer,"
the newspaper.
'Debt restructuring,
cost cutting, layoffs.'
Layoffs?
Any "Observer" employees
invited to the party?
So you're all reporters
for the, uh, "Observer."
'That's right.'
Xander Harrington--
man of the people, huh?
Inviting
the ink-stained wretches.
Xander was a good guy.
Did any of you hear
about the layoffs
that were coming up soon?
Layoffs?
What layoffs?
Well, actually, there's,
uh, quite a long list.
'Yeah. It appears that
no one is safe.'
'Must be very scary in the
newspaper business these days.'
That's a very lovely dress.
'Great color.'
Well, thank you.
[chuckles]
I'm Heather Evans.
Hello, Heather Evans.
You're very attractive.
It's probably why
your name's not on that list.
Good-looking women live
in a different world.
Excuse me? What's this list
you keep mentioning?
Oh, come on, Heather. The list
that was in the file
that you took
off Xander Harrington's desk.
Everyone here..
We mention layoffs,
and everyone
here reacts except you
'because you have read
the list.'
Oh, that's ridiculous.
I didn't go anywhere near
Xander's desk.
Bravo. Very well played,
considering the stress
you must be feeling right now.
You know, I was hoping
to dazzle you all
with my uncanny detective
skills, but you force me..
...you force me to just reveal
the humdrum facts
and point out that you have
blood on your shoes, Heather.
[Lisbon]
'Could you step out
of your shoe, ma'am?'
"Stop the presses"?
That's the phrase, right?
"Stop the presses."
Yeah. Got it.
Always wanted to say that.
[theme music]
Xander Harrington caught you
snooping in his office
and you killed him.
Now maybe
you didn't mean to do it.
You were surprised, scared--
No. I didn't even see him.
It was dark. No lights.
Curtains were drawn.
I went to the desk
I took the file..
...and I ran.
If I'd known he was..
My God,
I would never have..
How'd you know
that there was a list at all?
Someone told you. Who?
A confidential source.
And you'll go to jail
to protect this source?
Ed. Edward Harrington.
Xander's brother.
He, um..
He said there were gonna be
layoffs on Monday.
'I just,
I just wanted to know
'whether or not
I still had a job.'
- It's a very good job.
- Not anymore, it's not.
[Cho]
'Tell me exactly what
happened from the beginning.'
Ma'am? Is there, uh..
I-Is there something specific
that you wanted?
No. No.
Just keeping apprised.
Huh.
Alex Harrington
is the owner
of the seventh largest
media conglomerate in the world.
Yes, ma'am.
And you don't want
to disappoint a man
who owns 200 TV stations
and a national newspaper.
No, ma'am.
Looks like Heather's cleared.
Timeline puts her at the bar
at the time of the attack.
That's according to several male
guests who remember her well.
Figures. Only leaves 196 party
guests and 42 staff
as potential suspects.
Start with the brother.
Okay.
Take Rigsby.
Problem?
Nope. Not at all.
Ma'am? You're giving
my team assignments?
I know. I'm sorry.
Should've been your call.
I just want to make sure
those two can hack it.
Fair enough.
[Lisbon]
'The head of your
security said'
'that the house is fully wired,
but the family asked'
the cameras inside be
turned off? Why's that?
I take responsibility
for that.
No, it's my fault. I'm Tara--
Alex's wife. This is Ella.
And I'm the one who had
the cameras disconnected.
It's my fault.
It's nobody's fault,
dear. Hush.
Why'd you do it?
Cameras and panic rooms
and armed guards--
'it's a lot to take.'
I hated feeling watched
in my own home.
'Seems so silly now.'
I'm sorry. How long until you
take that horrible stuff down?
Forensics has promised
to release the crime scene
as soon as possible. I am
so sorry for any inconvenience.
[Ella whimpers]
Excuse me.
Uh, I'm too upset.
Uh, m-m-may I?
Thank you.
[laughs]
[Lisbon]
'You and Xander were close?'
He and Sadie were
my only true friends.
People seem more interested
in befriending
your money and connections
when you're married to
the C.E.O. Of Harrington media.
[Alex]
Yes, I suppose
it can be difficult at times.
By the way,
it'sformerC.E.O.
- Xander forced me out.
- 'Really?'
[Alex]
'Really.'
'He convened the board,
secured the necessary votes.'
Son staged a coup.
Yes.
You have any idea the guts
it takes to pull that off?
Xander proved he could lead.
I've never been prouder of him.
Proud of, uh, Eddie, too,
my other son.
[Patrick]
'Well, of course.'
But Xander had
the strength to lead, the guts.
That's important to you,
isn't it? Guts?
Of course. Guts, heart.
What else is there?
Spleen, liver, kidneys,
uh, genitalia.
Lot of important stuff there.
Are you being flippant
with me?
'My son is dead.'
Forgive me. I-I was.
Lost myself for a second.
Forgot where I was.
But, you know, that-that's
a very beautiful painting.
Very nice work, yeah.
Can I talk to you
for a moment?
[whispers] Quit that!
- What?
- Poking the bigwig.
"Poking the bigwig."
Ah, I like it.
It's got a nice ring to it.
I understand it's compulsion
you're not fully in control of
but I wish you would try.
It would make our work
a lot easier if you did...try.
- Did you see that?
- What?
Right outside that window.
There's a pink unicorn.
Amazing!
Now you're hallucinating.
No. No, no, look.
It's right outside the window.
Seriously, look.
It's a unicorn!
I want to see!
- I don't see a unicorn.
- It's right there.
[whispers]
I'm trying to trick her.
Oh. Yes.
What a nice unicorn.
'Yeah, very nice unicorn.'
So you like to have
secret tea parties?
How did you know
about the tea party?
Oh, you know, I kind of like
secret tea parties, too.
- I'm Patrick. That's Teresa.
- Hi.
I'm Ashley Harrington.
- It's a pleasure to meet you.
- You, too.
Now who's your mom and dad?
Xander Harrington
and Sadie Cardozo Harrington.
I know my address
and phone number, too.
Very good. Patrick and I are
actually looking for your mommy.
- Do you know where she is?
- Outside.
We could go cheer her up.
Is she sad, sweetie?
She misses daddy.
He went away on a trip.
'Yes, he did.'
Mr. Harrington, you prodded
Heather Evans into going
into your brother's office,
didn't you?
I told her
the file was on the desk.
What she did with that
information is her problem.
You're the west coast
head of media operations
and you tell an employee about
a confidential layoff list?
Well, I had
a feeling she'd be grateful.
And she was.
You exchanged the information
for sex.
Yes. I did.
Gate security
has you leaving the party
just before your brother died
of his injuries.
I didn't know what had happened,
and I didn't particularly want
to watch his coronation,
frankly. It's boring.
Forgive me, Xander.
Did you kill
your brother, Ed?
Would you give us a second?
No, I did not
kill my brother.
Well, you didn't seem
that sad about his death.
Well, maybe I just don't
display my emotions to cops.
Maybe.
Look, I'd like to tell you
that Xander and I
were the best of friends,
but we weren't.
We're just different people.
We weredifferent people.
He'd..
...always do the right things,
say the right things.
Dad would say, "jump."
he'd ask, "how high?"
And you?
Dad never asks me to jump.
- Mommy! Mommy!
- Baby, hmm?
- We're going to get ice cream.
- Okay. One scoop, okay?
[kisses]
No spoiling dinner.
- Okay.
- One scoop it is.
And I'll e-mail
you the Arizona overnights.
You've got that conference call
tomorrow with the affiliates.
- Okay. Thanks, Elizabeth.
- Come on.
You haven't told her?
[sighs]
How do you tell a six-year-old
her father's never coming home?
Well, she pretty much
knows already.
She just doesn't
understand it yet.
Nor do I. I just..
I keep thinking Xander would
know exactly what to say to her.
It's so stupid, huh?
Xander
must have had enemies..
...business rivals
that resented his success?
Um...sure.
Yeah, but nothing abnormal.
Well, there is
the "Visualize" thing.
The "Observer" is about to run
an investigative series
and it's gonna be
very critical.
Visualize?
The sort of religious group?
No, it's more like a cult.
It's brainwashing
with a sideline in tax fraud.
You know, we got
a-a pretty nasty letter
from their leader,
Bret Stiles
threatening unspecified
trouble if we ran it.
I can get you a copy.
Oh, you-you had me
at "cult."
Creepy.
What, you don't like
giant eyeballs?
No.
Hi. I'm Steven Wench.
Most folks call me
Brother Steve.
Are you the CBI folks
who called?
Yeah. Brother Patrick
and, uh, my brother Cho.
[Steve]
'Well, come this way.'
'I'm sorry, but I'm afraid
Mr. Stiles'
isn't on the premises today.
Where is he?
At this precise moment,
I don't know.
Bret lives spontaneously.
But I'm happy to help
with any questions.
I have a question.
Uh, what are they doing
in there with those gizmos?
That's where our technicians
assess for inner vision.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
That sounds fun.
Can anyone do that?
Um...sure.
Excellent. Cho, you got
the interview, right?
Just, uh, sign in.
Oh, yeah. Sure, sure.
- Hey.
- Hi, I wanna go.
- Have a seat.
- Cool.
Excellent.
Alright.
[imitates buzzer]
Just kidding.
W-what do I do?
Well, place your fingers
on the orb
and, uh, tell me your name.
You first.
David.
Hi, David. I'm Patrick.
Fingers on the orb.
'Do you find sadness
in the world around you?'
Yes.
Do you find yourself dwelling
on the misfortunes of your past?
Yeah.
Do you often think
people are secretly
out to get you?
Yes.
How you doing?
- How am I doing?
- Yeah.
Uh, how am I doing?
Well, Patrick
you have serious issues
with paranoia and depression
and negative thinking
in general.
What?
I would recommend our immersive
visualization program for you
as a matter of urgency.
Oh, okay. Um..
do-do-do you..
Do you take that?
Ah! Not so fast.
You thought you had me,
didn't you?
Maybe we should get going.
We gotta go get a warrant.
Before coming
to persecute us,
did you even look
at Xander Harrington's wife?
Sadie. We look at everyone, sir.
What about her?
We heard there was trouble
in her marriage.
If Xander divorced her,
there's a prenup.
But if he dies,
she gets it all.
Where'd you
hear that, Steve?
Do-do you have someone
on the inside?
I've said enough.
Please leave.
Do you have a gift shop?
'Cause I'd love
an eyeball mug or something.
- No.
- Okay.
[male #3]
Good job, Steven.
Good job. That was...
beautifully handled.
Thank you, Mr. Stiles.
No, thank you.
So the guy claims Stiles is only
threatening legal trouble
that visualize is a religion
of science and peace.
Tell that to the TV reporter
from Atlanta.
Last spring,
he went off on visualize
next day, he was flying
through the windshield
of a member's car.
One more thing. About Sadie
and Xander's marriage..
An affair?
No.
Xander and I have been
partners in everything
since the first week
of business school.
I loved him,
and I respected him.
I had no reason to stray.
Neither did he.
Sometimes you don't need
a reason.
Oh.
Agent Lisbon, you're here.
Something to report?
No, she just, um, thinks
I was screwing around
on your son.
Excuse me.
I have better things to do.
Do you think
she was having an affair?
On balance, no.
Go on.
Sadie loves this company,
as well as my son.
She'd never risk everything
for a roll in the hay.
Ambitious as all hell,
that girl.
I like it.
Don't get me wrong.
She's doubled our profit
since she took over
running the TV stations.
Um...
Excuse my rudeness.
[beeps]
Agent Lisbon.
Get everybody
out of the house.
- There's not enough time.
- Do what you can.
Tara! Sadie!
[cell phone rings]
[groans]
[beep]
Hello?
It's me. I need your help.
Lisbon, you need my help?
I need your help
finding a bomb.
There's still time. You're good
at this kind of thing.
If we find the bomb intact
maybe we can still
get rid of it.
What, are you nuts?
What do you want to do that for?
It's a bomb.
Just get out of there.
The guy's got comprehensive
home insurance, I'm sure.
Oh, come on, Jane. We've got
two minutes. Alright?
Where did they put it?
They said it was somewhere
in the grand salon.
Well, if they called it
the grand salon
then obviously
they're insiders.
Good point.
Uh, l-leading us where?
'Uh, let me see.'
'Uh, if I was familiar
with that room'
'I would plant a bomb..'
'Try under the sofa.
No, no, no, no, no.'
'The cupboard over by the Dutch
forgery in the corner.'
Uh, th-the painting?
How do you know it's a forgery?
'Eh, the brushwork,
it's all wrong.'
'It's way too loose.'
- Oh, my God. You were right.
- 'Yeah, well, of course.'
That looser feeling didn't
develop until much later on.
No! The bomb. I found it.
One minute left.
Oh, good. Time to leave.
Get out of there.
Lisbon, if you think
I am even gonna engage
in this game
of "which wire to pull"
I'm not interested.
I don't wanna play that game.
'Just leave right now.
Run. Okay?'
- You're right. I'm outta here.
- Thank you. Good.
Where's mommy?
- Hang on.
- 'Ashley?'
- Ashley, we have to leave now.
- No!
'Lisbon!'
Ashley, get out
from under there. Ashley.
No! No! I want my mommy!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What's going on there?
'Ashley, come on.'
No! Leave me alone!
I want my mommy!
Come out! You come out now!
That's an order!
Lisbon, pick up
the girl and leave.
Just pick her up
and take her outside.
You can do that.
Run away now.
Lisbon?
Oh, God.
Lisbon!
No, no, no, no.
Screw it.
Lisbon!
You are a very bad girl.
[sighs]
You're a bad girl.
Agent Lisbon.
Thank you.
Thank you for saving
my granddaughter.
We are so grateful.
It's all part of the service.
No, you were brave
and resourceful
and I'll make sure
your supervisors say as much
'in your file.'
Look, if there's ever anything
I can do for you personally
please don't hesitate.
Well, you could offer her
the pad
for a weekend during the summer.
Actually, uh, I was wondering
if I could speak
with some of your staff
who had access to that room.
Ah, Edward.
Thank you for joining us.
I just heard what happened.
Is everyone alright?
Oh, everyone's fine. It's fine.
Well, if there's anything I can
do to help
just say the word. I'm here.
Actually, uh, I'll be
issuing an announcement
and I wanted to let
you and Sadie know first.
Announcements?
Ooh, I love announcements.
Um, sh-should we order up
a round of cocktails?
I'll make this quick.
Uh, as much as it pains me
to discuss business
at a time like this..
But the fact is,
we do have shareholders,
and the board has demanded a new
C.E.O. be announced immediately.
[whispers]
Sadie, I bet.
- Uh..
- Sadie. Wow.
'Uh... Ed, I-I'm sorry.'
No. No, that's okay.
That's.. It's your right
to name whoever you want.
Uh, I-I don't know
what to say, Ed. I'm..
No, it's okay. It's, um...
I get it. I get it.
Um, I'm sure you'll do
a great job. Congratulations.
Okay...
Well, I'm not gonna
say anything.
The bomb threat..
We got something.
It came from the phone
of Elizabeth Stanfeld.
Sadie Harrington's assistant.
Let's go get that warrant.
Nice work.
Thanks.
Kitchen's clear.
Bedroom, too.
Van Pelt been
acting weird to you?
Pleasedon't talk to me
about Van Pelt.
No, I won't. Has she?
No.
It's just she's..
She's been smiling at me.
No kidding.
Sometimes I think
she might still be into me.
That'd be weird, huh?
You're weird.
Cold.
You know, I don't think
Stanfeld's been here in a while.
Hey, check this out.
"Visualize. A tool for living."
'Elizabeth Stanfeld's
a member of visualize.'
Looks like Bret Stiles is gonna
be talking to us after all.
The eye is not
just the window to the soul.
It is the key
to unlocking your greatness.
because when you see it,
you will be it.
[Bret]
'One more time.'
The eye is not just
the window to the soul.
It is the key
to unlocking your greatness.
[Patrick]
'Excuse me. I'm sorry. Uh..'
The eye is the key?
Or the window? Or is it both?
I'm a little confused.
Mr. Jane, I presume.
- Yeah.
- Hello. Welcome.
Oh, you're expecting us?
Oh, yes. And I presume this is
your long-suffering colleague
agent Lisbon.
If I may say, she is
more beautiful than advertised.
Oh, thanks, guy.
Take a little break. Thank you.
Give us a few minutes.
Thank you.
[clears throat]
Elizabeth Stanfeld..
...your, um... "dear friend
and fine student"
she planted a bomb
at the Harringtons' house
'a bomb she couldn't have
possibly made herself.'
Lisbon here defused it.
Heroine.
Oh. Well, I-I'm..
I mean, I may have taught her.
Uh... Stanfeld?
Oh.
Uh, w-was she a brunette?
Mr. Stiles, "dear friend"?
Well, yeah, but, you know
I've signed millions
of these in my time.
I always like
to personalize them.
It's a little trick I learned
from an old friend of mine
Ronnie Reagan.
So you have no knowledge
of this woman?
You have no knowledge
of any attacks
on the Harrington family?
That's your position, is it?
No, it's not my position.
Actually, it's the truth.
My eyes aren't, uh...
windows or doors
or even keys,
for that matter.
I use 'em
to look at things
and what I'm looking at
right now is a big, fat liar.
[chuckles]
Really?
Really. Yes. Betrayed
by a faint facial tremor.
You could work on that
in the mirror.
You'd get
some great results.
Mm.
You know, now I see why..
...Red John really enjoys
sparring with you.
A worthy adversary, yeah?
Yes.
Straight for the jugular.
Obviously,
you struck a nerve.
Hmm.
Losing a wife and a child
like that..
Well, it makes
a man reckless, untethered.
'Fills him with anger and shame'
'that he cannot express.'
Well, must makeyourjob
very hard, hmm?
Yes, but the health
plan's great.
[chuckles]
Mr. Jane,
I think we can help you.
I think we can scrub
that shame and grief
and self-hatred
right out of your system.
Bret, please.
[laughs]
We both know what you are.
I mean, let's be honest here.
You're a con man.
I mean, you're very charming,
and you're very good at it
but you're just a con man.
And you could no more help me
than you can fly to the moon.
Mm.Nowwho's struck a nerve?
Nobody's past helping..
...even you.
Believe me
when I say this, Bret
you don't want
to make this personal.
Now give us Stanfeld
or I will make it
my sole purpose to hound you
for the rest
of your miserable, phony life.
[laughs]
Whoa.
Am I hearing a threat here?
I mean, a-aren't there rules
about this sort of thing? Hmm?
Like you said, untethered.
'Mr. Stiles'
the percentage play here
is to give us Stanfeld.
She's not gonna betray you.
She's loyal.
Forget it, Lisbon.
I'm bored.
Elizabeth is at
Edward Harrington's penthouse.
She went to Edward?
To do what?
I don't know.
Uh, she didn't tell me.
I gave her no instructions.
She went of her
own free will.
'Have a nice day.'
Rigsby, get to Ed Harrington's
place immediately.
[moans]
Police! Don't move!
- Let me see your hands! Freeze!
- Mr. Harrington?
Mr. Harrington,
are you...alright?
Yep. I think he's...fine.
What the hell
is going on?
[Rigsby]
'See, the way
it looks from here'
'is that you and Elizabeth
were in this together.'
Take out Xander
take out your father
live happily ever after
with her and Bret Stiles.
No. I'm not into
that visualize crap.
If I had any idea, I..
Uh, she was just..
...just a friend.
Convenient, though, that
she seems intent on taking out
everyone between you and the top
job at Harrington media.
Was Sadie next?
How do you know
Iwasn't next?
Visualize wanted to kill us all
because of that idiotic story.
Then why didn't
she kill you, Ed?
'I-I don't know.'
- 'You ever meet Bret Stiles?'
- No.
Anyone at all
from the visualize organization?
No.
So let me get this straight..
she was sleeping with you
because you were a Harrington
but not an important enough
Harrington to kill. Is that it?
So, you're a stooge.
Yeah, I'm a stooge.
Thanks for the heads-up.
So Bret Stiles claims
you acted alone.
But you had
an accomplice, didn't you?
An accomplice to what?
The bombing attempt.
We've got your phone records.
Slam dunk. 20 years.
2 decades.
7,000 days living in a box.
'I don't know how people do it.'
[Cho]
'Now help yourself out here.'
We know
someone gave you that bomb.
you didn't kill Xander.
Sadie Harrington was with you
the entire party.
- Of course I didn't kill him.
- But you know who did.
Give us a name,
and we can talk a deal.
I'm looking down at you
from a great height.
'You're like ants.'
It's sad how far
I am beyond you people..
...spiritually and mentally.
Mm. But, uh, physically
I think we, uh,
we might have the upper hand.
And physically is kinda
how they roll in prison.
Just because
you've stopped my work
doesn't mean others
won't follow in my path.
'You can't imprison the truth.'
Oh, Lizzy, you are
batnuts crazy. Batnuts, girl.
But that's okay. You're young.
Youcanrecover your wits.
'You're gonna have to work
very hard'
but you've given me
a very good idea
and I thank you.
Excuse me. We've come
to take my son home.
This is a family matter.
I'm sorry, sir, but we haven't
finished questioning him.
Edward made a mistake. It was
dangerous, yes, but not criminal
so unless you have some evidence
linking him to a crime
I'd like you to let him go.
Let the poor wretch go,
Van Pelt.
He's guilty of nothing except
extremely poor decision-making
sexual partner-wise,
and, uh..
...who hasn't been there?
Jane.
It isn't in my authority
to allow that, sir
'but if you'll wait a moment,
I'll find agent Lisbon'
'and she may be able
to help you out.'
- 'Dad?'
- 'Never mind. There he is.'
'Eddie, we're leaving.'
You bastard!
You stupid son of a bitch!
How could you endanger us?
Ashley was nearly killed.
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna go wait
in the car.
I'm really sorry.
You're sorry? Sorry?
Have you
no common sense, boy?
Are you completely--
Sir, you're gonna have
to take it easy.
Anyhow, here we are. Let's go
home and discuss this.
[Van Pelt]
'Mr. Harrington, that
isn't going to be possible.'
[ring]
Oh, hell. Not again.
- What's wrong?
- Miserable cowards.
- More threats!
- What does it say?
"Next time
you won't be so lucky."
Sent from the same number
as the earlier threat.
I thought you had traced
that call to Stanfeld.
Well, they likely use
the same number
for many different cloned cells.
It proves it's
the same people, anyhow.
Meaning Visualize.
Agent Hightower,
I'm going to need
additional protection
for my family
at least until we can get
to the house in London.
Mr. Harrington, while your
family's safety is at stake
maybe it's best
to postpone the expose.
If I gave in,
where does it stop?
My family would be
under constant threat
from people who don't like
what I print or air.
We need protection,
Agent Hightower.
Mr. Harrington, the police
assigned to you
are very well-trained
personnel. We can add more if--
I want your best people..
Ms. Lisbon and her team.
I'll insist on it.
Mr. Harrington, that's
very flattering, but you--
And if you could release
my son now, I'd appreciate it.
I'll see what we can do.
She's about to throw out
the queen of spades.
Stop showing off.
[sighs]
Ha.
[Patrick]
'That's what's called'
'cutting off your nose
to spite your face.'
[cell phone rings]
- I'll take that. Thank you.
- Lisbon.
- Goodnight, everyone.
- Goodnight.
Alex, I told Ash she could stay
up if you tucked her in.
- Is that okay?
- Absolutely.
Thank you.
Night, sweetie.
Perimeter's clear, boss.
'Just checked in
with the guards outside.'
Gin. There you go.
Who's next? Any takers?
[clicks]
- Wish me luck.
- Uh-huh.
- Double.
- Sure.
[clatter]
'Mm.'
You're a lucky man.
- No such thing as luck.
- Really?
It's all about knowing
the odds, seizing the chances.
'No luck involved.'
Hogwash.
Hogwash?
You heard me. Hogwash.
What's that?
- What?
- Shh!
[Lisbon]
'What are you..'
[Patrick]
'Shh!'
Wait a minute.
I hear it, too.
[whispers]
I got Ashley covered here.
It's coming from in there.
[whispers]
Xander's office?
It's been sealed
since the murder.
[sighs]
[switch clicks]
Clear.
Wow. Could've sworn
I heard someone in here.
Oh, what's this?
[chuckles]
That's Ashley's.
- So?
- 'That's it.'
What's it?
She was here.
She was right here.
- What's he talking about?
- No idea.
That's why she's been
so quiet and withdrawn.
She witnessed the murder.
[alarm wailing]
[Lisbon]
'The power's been cut.'
Uh...w-we have
a-a backup generator.
[Van Pelt]
'Perimeter's been breached.
Someone's on the grounds.'
Copy that, Van Pelt.
Charlie king one,
check the grounds.
do you copy?
'Charlie king one?'
'We're on our way
to the safe room.'
'Secure Tara, Sadie
and the baby. Go!'
Come on.
- Seal the door now.
- Mm.
[lock clicks]
[voice breaks]
Grandpa?
[chuckles]
It's okay, honey.
Don't be scared.
We're safe in here.
Everything's gonna be
alright.
Come on.
There you go.
Oh, I could do
with some Chocolate.
You have any, uh,
chocolate, Grace?
- No.
- Just a little bit?
- Van Pelt, what's the status?
- Lisbon, that was very good.
I have one question.
Who the hell is Charlie king?
Call it up.
[taps keys]
[clicks]
I want mommy.
Hey, you remember the party
we had a few days ago?
With all the flowers
and music?
That's right.
You were in daddy's office
that afternoon
before the guests got here
for the party, remember?
Uh, were you maybe..
...hiding under his desk?
Playing tea party?
It's alright if you were.
You won't get in trouble.
Tell grandpa
the truth, sweetheart.
[sighs]
Ashley...
'if you were there'
'maybe you saw the game'
'grandpa was playing
with daddy.'
Did you?
What the hell is going on?
Uh, we--it's a very clever plan.
Would you like me to explain?
Wait. Why are they in the safe
room? What are you doing?
Ma'am, if you'll come with me,
I'll explain everything.
'I want to know.'
Thirty seconds
and I'm pulling the plug.
Daddy's dead, isn't he?
It was a game.
When your daddy fell.. I
t was an accident.
I didn't mean to do it.
[lowered voice]
Cho.
Put your hands
on your head.
Now.
You're under arrest.
[sighs]
You're a bastard!
Uh, well,
thanks for the, uh, feedback.
Always appreciated.
What's wrong with grandpa?
It's okay, baby.
It's okay.
You've got nothing.
My lawyers will
grind this to dust.
Don't say a single thing,
either of you.
They're saying I killed Xan.
Well, that's not true, right?
Of course not.
It was very sweet
seeing you with Ashley.
Uh, I guess after two sons
when she came along,
it lit up your world.
Strange, though,
that you can't
so much as look
at your own daughter
nor barely touch
your lovely wife.
How'd you find out
the baby wasn't yours?
I know that you believed Tara
was having an affair with Xander
and that your son was
Ella's biological father.
'And you were partly right.'
'I mean, she was having an
affair with your son'
but it wasn't with Xander.
Was it, Ed?
Huh?Oh!
Yeah, I figured it out
when I saw you two at the CBI.
She was very angry
with you, very angry.
'Pure jealousy.'
Oh, my God.
I'm..
Ella's father.
Congratulations.
She's a real peach, actually.
She's great.
No. Can't be.
[whispers]
I am so sorry.
No! It was Xander!
It was Xander.
Okay. We'll take that
as a confession.
- Thank you.
- Come on. Let's go.
You really don't think
I can do anything, do you?
- It can't be.
- Well, it is. Sorry.
You killed the wrong son.
[gasps]
Xander and Tara
seemed too close.
Always whispering together
in the corners
breaking apart
when I'd come into the room.
They were friends.
They were probably talking
about her affair with Ed.
So I ordered
a paternity test.
The results came back
the day of the party.
Ella is not my child..
...but you know
that already, don't you?
What did you expect, dad?
You treat her like just another
one of your possessions
but she's not!
[Alex]
'I confronted Xan.'
- You betrayed me!
- He didn't deny it.
Why didn't he just deny it?
[Patrick]
'He just naturally assumed
you knew it was Ed.'
You!
Aah!
When I think..
...of what poor Ashley saw..
...she didn't see anything.
I made it up.
But the teacup,
she was there.
[whispers]
Yes, I know.
But it's all in the wrist.
[Bret]
'My good friend Senator Aleman'
is very concerned
about my treatment.
Of course, youdoknow
the good senator, huh?
Chair of
the justice committee.
I know him.
Bret Stiles.
Good to see you.
Looking sharp.
[clears throat]
I mean, I'd hate to tell him
that you failed to resolve
this matter.
So why don't we
resolve it right now?
- Mm.
- Good.
Patrick, Mr. Stiles
here says that
you antagonized him
and conducted yourself
in a way that reflected
poorly on the bureau.
Do you have anything
to say?
Uh, no.
I'm-I'm good, thanks.
Okay.
Actually, there's one thing
I'd like to say.
Is this gonna be helpful,
Patrick?
- Probably not.
- Okay, then, there you go.
Nice talking with you.
What? You're-you're kidding,
right? That's it?
No. Do give my best
to Senator Aleman.
Is he still seeing
that stripper in Bakersfield?
'Lovely girl.'
Well, well.
I can see that
I've met my match here.
You two..
...quite the double act.
Ah. I will retreat,
chastened.
By the way..
...we will find a way to charge
you with that attempted bombing.
Miss Hightower, shh.
Don't push your luck.
So long, Bret.
Don't draw the
wrong lesson here, Patrick.
I've got Stiles checkmated.
But if a player
with real juice came in here
I'd want to see
you dance for him.
Isn't that what we just did?
You know what I mean.
Okay.
And I do love to dance.
Stay tuned for scenes
from our next episode.